Notify the drone formation
to launch all their missiles
straight at Champion City.
This tactic
isn't exactly by the book.
There are no rules on the battlefield.
Fire!
Yes, sir!
The Blue Force has gone completely mad.
They're really going to level Champion City.
Yeah.
This Wu Dazhou...
really has some guts.
Blue Force drone formation sustained 100% battle damage.
I never expected
Guo Zijian
to be such a brilliant commander.
Report!
We have successfully located the Blue Force command vehicle.
Then what are you waiting for?
Fire!
Yes, sir!
What's going on?
Report, Captain Wu.
The command vehicle is locked on by a Red Force drone.
Bail out now!
If you want to take prisoners, you should switch weapons.
I don't like taking prisoners.
Then what?
I'll give you a chance.
Let's fight.
Bring it on.
Come on.
Alright.
I'm done.
I can't beat you.
And you can hardly beat me either.
I don't mean to lecture you guys,
but could you show some class?
Zero sportsmanship.
For a Support Team captain,
you smile all day long,
but you hit pretty hard.
Just you wait.
This video
must be saved as a classic clip.
I really want to know
how he plans to get back at
that actor, Guo Zijian.
I really didn't expect
the Special Forces to be completely defeated.
How unexpected.
As for today's report,
I'll have plenty to write about.
Challenging each other right after the drill.
These two boys
have way too much energy.
They're young.
Of course they have boundless energy.
Besides,
who would want to admit defeat?
Are we really not stopping them?
Why should we?
Combat is a normal way of communicating.
Fair point.
Your training camp here
is full of hidden talents.
That Yang Maolin is quite a fighter.
I didn't expect a commander like you
to be no slouch either.
But for today's match,
let's call it a draw.
Sure.
At the very least,
I had to save some face for my superior.
Give it a rest.
Your chest still hurts, doesn't it?
I'm just worried your ribs
will be complaining until dark.
Coming here this time,
I thought about it.
If
I had been
around Li Songwei
a little more cautious,
or if I had anticipated
that kid Yang Maolin's
sneak attack just a bit,
it wouldn't have ended like this.
Throughout history,
the hardest cognitive trap
for a loser to escape
is the word "if."
That's not the same thing.
How is it not?
I came here this time
for your top three fighters.
But no one expected
they couldn't take a punch.
I mean, you are the
captain of the Support Team.
Earlier you were leading your men
to serve us tea and water.
In the blink of an eye,
you've all become elite soldiers.
You pulled this huge twist on me
and taught me a lesson.
Is that your excuse for saying "what if"?
What else could it be?
I have to go back and write a self-criticism,
so I need a valid reason, right?
I actually have a way
to help your report get approved.
Let's hear it.
Just say
the 8th Army originally planned
for my team, Guo Zijian's team.
The top three were just a decoy,
to throw you off the scent.
Stop flattering yourself,
okay?
Who would believe that?
Never mind if it's true or not,
as long as you pass, it's fine.
You're really arrogant.
But that's fine.
If I really do as you say,
I'd be selling out your
Deputy Army Commander Liang
completely.
By the way,
I also called someone over.
Who?
Report.
Captain Wu,
you Special Forces guys
sure have a good eye.
You were completely fooled by the Support Team captain here.
If you ask me,
he's as blind as a bat.
That's because he had preconceived notions.
Now that he's come to his senses,
he found both key figures at once.
It seems
he's going to conduct a thorough after-action review.
Captain Wu,
you called me over saying there's an important mission.
You're not going to pick a fight with me too, are you?
With my amateur skills,
I'm no match for that.
Staff Officer Liang's value
isn't in her fists.
I'd like to ask first,
someone like Staff Officer Liang,
an electronic warfare expert,
how did you trick her into coming here?
He begged me.
That's right.
He had to beg me repeatedly.
And it's just a temporary team.
All right.
Then I won't beat around the bush.
The reason I invited you both here today
is actually because I want
to hear directly from you
the real reason for my failure.
From a tactical perspective,
we did gain some advantage.
What do you mean?
When you were engaging Jiang Shengqiang,
I was in charge of the relevant support.
Right at that time,
I noticed
your command and communication
methods and habits.
No wonder.
Let me tell you,
our electronic warfare expert this time
had never lost before.
But he stumbled when facing you.
We went back and reviewed it several times,
but couldn't find the reason.
Turns out, you were the problem.
But I still don't really get it.
You were just a
support unit.
And you weren't even on the scene.
The information you could get was very limited.
Based purely on that premise,
you dared let Yang Maolin venture deep alone?
As for the specific details and
certain concepts involved,
I can't explain them in detail.
But what I can tell Captain Wu is,
regarding some electronic signals
and the transmission of information,
as well as within a short time,
formulating more than one counter-plan,
these things, to me,
have already become instinctual reactions.
Instinct?
Impressive.
Of course,
this alone isn't enough.
The most important factor is Captain Guo.
Our Captain Guo's
battlefield awareness,
his anticipation of the opponent,
and his ad-hoc responses,
all of these greatly complemented
and assisted me
in various electronic countermeasures,
ensuring the effective execution of tactics.
That is the key to victory.
How rare.
First time you've praised me like this.
I'm not even used to it.
I'm not praising you.
This is a professional discussion.
I can tell.
However,
after hearing Staff Officer Liang's combat analysis,
I did come to a conclusion.
Your one plus one
is greater than two.
You've taken single combat branches
and reintegrated them into a
brand new combat unit.
Even though it looks
a lot like our army's Special Forces,
in reality,
regarding three-dimensional adaptability on the battlefield,
it has a much broader scope.
Captain Wu,
you truly are an expert in new-type combat forces.
You grasped the key point instantly.
After hearing what you said,
I can say this trip wasn't in vain.
Captain Guo,
what do you think?
I'm thinking about what you just said:
the whole is greater than the sum of its parts.
So where exactly does the future direction
of our new-type forces lie?
No one can really say for sure what the future holds.
We're all figuring it out as we go.
We've been discussing this constantly.
However, after your intensive training,
the outcome remains an unknown.
If you are disbanded,
then you'll all go back to your original units.
It'll be like sprinkling spice
across the various group armies.
But if you stay together...
You've reached the crucial point.
Why did you stop?
These crucial matters
must be handled by crucial people.
All right.
I've said what I needed to say.
Staff Officer Liang.
Sorry to take up your time.
Thanks for coming.
All right, you two talk.
I'll wait for you outside.
Captain Wu.
Any other pointers?
Key positions, key personnel.
It seems Wu Dazhou
has thoroughly grasped
the underlying purpose and significance
of this confrontation.
Even the theater commanders' secrets
are going to be exposed.
This Wu Dazhou...
Regardless,
for the two teams
to be able to frankly
discuss development models
is a good thing.
It also allows the theater commanders
to see
the new-type combat forces'
attempts under different models.
Let me tell you,
this Staff Officer Liang
is a real game-changer.
If you build a team in the future,
you absolutely can't do without her.
What team?
Once the training is over,
I'll go back to being an instructor.
Nice and relaxing.
I won't worry about this anymore.
Drop the act.
As soon as the arena match ended,
I sent out a whole team
to gather information on you everywhere.
Holding such a grudge?
A soldier who doesn't hold grudges
is just a sucker.
I, Guo Zijian, am a blank slate,
I can't withstand such scrutiny, brother.
You call yourself a blank slate?
Captain Guo.
After I went back
and looked at your background and experience,
to be honest,
I was quite astounded.
If the two of us are fated,
it would definitely be on the battlefield
as the closest life-and-death partners.
Peace is the highest reward for a soldier.
None of us want war.
Since we can't be life-and-death partners,
let's be rivals on the training ground,
and sharpen each other.
All right.
I'll definitely
strike harder each time.
We'll see about that.
The show's over.
Deputy Director Deng.
We should head out too.
I didn't expect that
after knowing each other for just two days,
they'd become fast friends.
You don't know someone until you fight them.
Heroes recognize heroes.
Don't you think
Wu Dazhou was hinting at something earlier?
Do you think he called us here
just to save face,
and have a simple debrief?
Isn't that the case?
I don't think this is
just a conversation between him and us.
Someone else is behind him.
You mean
their coming to challenge us this time
wasn't just a typical showdown?
Right.
I'm afraid this is
a test by the higher-ups on the army group's
development of new-type combat forces.
In that case,
we must have passed the test, right?
I'm afraid it's not that simple.
Regardless,
you should thank Wu Dazhou.
Yes, I really should thank him.
I wanted to challenge the champion before,
but I also said
it probably wouldn't go so smoothly.
But Wu Dazhou actually
solved this problem for me.
Congratulations.
After this challenge is over,
looks like you'll be reinstated right away.
If I get reinstated,
would you be willing to be my chief staff officer?
I'm afraid I can't.
After the training ends,
I'll be going to the research institute in Beijing
to report for duty.
Listen, Wu Dazhou,
how many years have you been a soldier?
You're leaking secrets,
do you know that?
I didn't say anything, sir.
You didn't say anything directly,
but everything you said
was clearly tipping off Guo Zijian.
That really wasn't my intention.
You're overthinking it.
Go back and write a self-criticism.
Reflect thoroughly on this failure.
Yes, sir.
Deputy Director Deng,
actually, this time,
we didn't completely fail.
At the very least,
we helped Commander Jiang
discover someone like Guo Zijian, didn't we?
You're going to Beijing.
I was only here on secondment anyway.
Going to Beijing
was the plan from the very beginning.
Beijing.
That's nice.
It's just a bit of a shame.
A shame about what?
It's just that what you're doing now,
this research project,
should really be embedded with frontline troops,
to participate more in actual combat.
Like this training session,
once you go to Beijing,
you might not get opportunities like this.
But going to Beijing has its perks.
Once I'm in Beijing,
I can get access to
the most cutting-edge theories
and military tech advancements.
That may be true,
but practice is the sole criterion for testing truth.
True.
Practice tests theory,
but theory also guides practice.
They complement each other.
Neither is more important than the other.
After I leave for Beijing,
if you have any questions,
you can always ask me.
If I can't solve it,
I still have my mentors
and professors.
After all,
the academic atmosphere in Beijing
and its resources
are a bit better.
Commander,
To be honest,
being in our own camp
makes me feel at ease.
Yeah.
I came back to handle some paperwork,
and I feel exactly the same way.
As for the training team,
is there any news?
In his report, Deputy Director Deng,
despite his objections to
the New Quality Combined Force
being formed,
has nevertheless
undoubtedly boosted Guo Zijian and the training team's
influence and visibility.
How is it?
Feeling a bit jealous, aren't you?
Commander,
to say it doesn't bother me,
I'm not that broad-minded.
But for pushing Guo Zijian forward,
I don't regret it.
Actually, he was already
prepared for battle.
Even if I didn't light this fuse,
he'd find a way to make it go off himself.
According to what you're saying,
Guo Zijian's victory
is greatly discounted.
First, in front of Wu Dazhou,
he pretended to be a docile
Support Team captain.
Then he used you
to provoke his anger.
Wu Dazhou, that fool,
underestimated the enemy
and acted on impulse.
No wonder he lost.
Whether he underestimated the enemy
or acted on impulse,
Wu Dazhou deserved to lose this battle.
Guo Zijian
was prepared for battle long ago.
Actually, this battle
was originally meant for me.
How so?
Guo Zijian had long planned
to challenge the titleholder.
But unexpectedly,
Wu Dazhou
stole my role.
It seems
Guo Zijian has a lot of confidence in you.
He knew
you could definitely win this title.
Sometimes,
the one who understands you
isn't necessarily your comrade,
but more often your opponent.
This Guo Zijian...
I really thought
he was content
being the Support Team captain.
I didn't expect him
to put up a front
while secretly making his move.
It's understandable.
His battalion commander was dismissed,
and he became the Support Team captain.
If he didn't endure hardship to bounce back,
he wouldn't be a real man.
It seems this setback
really taught him a lesson.
Quietly,
he did everything he needed to do.
On this point alone,
I admit I fall short.
You shouldn't be too modest.
Since the group army
set up this arena,
they will definitely give you, the titleholder,
a proper explanation.
Besides,
I'm still the deputy captain of the training team.
When it's time to speak up,
I won't hold back.
Understood.
Staff Officer Liang.
Can you come down for a minute?
Yes, I'm right downstairs.
Okay.
Captain Guo, what's wrong?
Can you spare a minute
to chat?
Let's walk.
Have you heard?
After the training program ends,
the group army is forming a New Quality Combined Force.
I heard Deputy Army Commander Liang mention it.
Don't you have any thoughts about it?
The training camp is probably meant to
select talent for the New Quality Combined Force.
Through this victory,
your chances of getting selected are high.
I'm not talking about myself.
I'm talking about you.
Me?
I think the New Quality Combined Force
really needs talent like you.
If you go to Beijing,
you'll just be a military researcher.
But if you stay here,
I promise
you can continue your research project.
So,
stay.
You won't regret it.
How can you promise that?
I...
Guo Zijian,
let's make a deal.
What deal?
If you can become
the leader of the New Quality Combined Force,
then I'll consider staying.
It's a deal.
Lao Suo.
Because the feasibility study of this new project
is quite tedious,
lately,
my time on duty has been intermittent.
Thanks for your hard work.
Not at all.
It's all part of my job.
Actually,
during my mission this time,
I also had some selfish motives.
I specifically submitted a report to the leaders,
to have you act as the brigade commander.
Thank you for your high regard, Commander Yang.
Actually, I still feel that I
lack the capability,
and I've disappointed everyone.
No need to be so polite with me.
After coming back this time,
I found that all the brigade's work
has greatly improved.
Commissar Kang also speaks highly of your work.
Actually, he's the one holding it all together.
Originally, I wanted to give you
a few days off after I came back.
I didn't expect the group army to organize another
key training for new-type combat forces.
And you were drafted again
to be the deputy captain of the training team.
What do they say?
A loud drum needs a heavy mallet.
I have nothing more to add.
Just keep up the good work.
Seeing that this training is ending soon,
there is something
I want to remind you of.
What is it?
Before long,
I will fully devote myself to
the research of the new subject.
I won't be able to manage both anymore.
I understand.
Then I'll congratulate you in advance, Commander Yang.
It's a lateral transfer.
Just a change of job.
Nothing to congratulate me for.
But after I leave,
regarding the position of brigade commander,
what are your thoughts?
I will obey the organization's arrangements.
The higher-ups have also talked to me.
My opinion is very clear.
I won't say anything against our principles.
I hope you'll work harder during this period,
and achieve more results.
I definitely won't disappoint
the high expectations of the leaders.
There is one thing
I know you've been worried about.
It's about the last drill
where we suffered a defeat.
I'm telling you clearly now,
this matter and your appointment
have no direct connection.
Go all out and do it.
Yes, sir.
I'll give my all
to the organization.
You're back.
How is it?
We've prepared a huge feast.
Are you satisfied?
Brigade Commander Suo.
A bit too early.
The orders haven't come down yet.
Isn't it just a matter of time?
With your seniority and ability,
you should have been promoted long ago.
Let me tell you,
we're speaking behind closed doors here.
Don't let others hear you.
It would reflect badly if the leaders found out.
I know, I know.
I'm just happy for you.
Anyway,
until it's official,
don't speak too soon.
You're just too tense.
Brigade Commander Yang
formally spoke with me today.
Really?
So it's settled then?
To be honest,
if this were in the past,
I wouldn't care about being the brigade commander.
It's different now.
This new-type forces training team
is the testing ground for military reform.
Once I become the brigade commander,
I'll have the authority to formulate plans.
I want them all to see
that this tree of mine, Suo Jian'an,
can bear some truly good fruit.
Anyway, as long as our Lao Suo is around,
the fruit on this tree
will definitely grow big and round.
Pretty much.
Lao Suo,
the training team is about to graduate.
Regarding this graduation report,
do you have any thoughts?
The graduation report?
Jiang Shengqiang.
He is the champion of this competition,
so having him write the graduation report
is entirely well-deserved.
What about Guo Zijian?
Guo Zijian...
Indeed.
Guo Zijian defeated Wu Dazhou.
But
I think it's mainly because his
role as the Support Team captain confused the opponent.
It was somewhat opportunistic.
Most importantly,
although he's in the training team,
he's responsible for the support work.
He didn't participate in any training.
If we let him write it,
I'm afraid there'll be criticism.
But
Guo Zijian led the training team
and defeated Wu Dazhou.
This is an indisputable fact.
I remember the recruitment notice stated
that all personnel of the training team
could sign up regardless of their roles.
So at a time like this,
excluding him
isn't that a bit unreasonable?
It's not about excluding him.
You might not know this,
but he withdrew his application halfway through.
So he's no longer under consideration.
Lao Suo,
the purpose of our recruitment notice
is to select talent.
Since right now,
both Jiang Shengqiang and Guo Zijian
are rare talents,
I think maybe we can do this.
Let both of them
each draft a graduation report proposal.
We'll select the better one.
What do you think?
You mean draft two proposals?
One from each of them?
I think it's a great idea.
It's settled then.
You win! You win!
You've got way too much stamina.
We aren't that far apart in age,
so why is the gap in our physical fitness so huge?
I know, right?
I'm wondering that too.
We're of the same age,
so why is the gap in our open-mindedness
so huge?
You really never have a good word to say.
Alright, Liu Wangyuan.
It's been a while since we played ball.
Tell me.
What do you want from me?
Got some new inside info?
What inside info?
Let me ask you.
The new-type core training team
is about to graduate.
You keep hiding in the Second Battalion instead of going back.
What's the meaning of this?
Are you just going to hand over your hard-earned honor?
A defeated general
has no honor to speak of.
This is why I say,
you've really let Deputy Brigade Commander Suo down after all his mentoring.
What are you trying to say?
About the graduation report,
Deputy Brigade Commander Suo told you, right?
He did.
You can't just brush it off.
Whoever represents the training team
to give this graduation report
will directly affect the future.
It decides who becomes the core figure of the New Quality Combined Force.
You know that?
I know.
Just knowing isn't enough.
How about this?
Later, I'll have someone
from our Operations and Training Section
send over some reference materials to you.
You need to put in some serious effort these next few days.
No matter what,
you must secure this spot, understand?
Don't take it lightly.
And definitely don't let it go to
that kid Guo Zijian.
Liu Wangyuan.
Tell me the truth.
Do you feel that
Guo Zijian leads the 1st Battalion better than you do?
Deep down,
are you a little bit jealous?
As if!
Me, jealous of him?
He just got blindly lucky
and won once.
Do you think that completely redeems him?
Liu Wangyuan,
it's really easy
for you to say that.
You try it. Come on.
If you're so capable, let's see you
get blindly lucky against someone like Wu Dazhou.
Jiang Shengqiang,
you're truly selfless.
Deputy Brigade Commander Suo already made you the titleholder.
Then Wu Dazhou came out of nowhere.
And of all things,
it ended up firing up Guo Zijian.
Deputy Brigade Commander Suo
looks at the big picture.
Whoever beats Wu Dazhou,
he's happy about it.
But think carefully, is it really that simple?
No matter what anyone says,
Guo Zijian was parachuted in halfway through.
Do you think
he can truly represent our 396th Brigade?
So,
if the new-type combat forces
can truly form a combined unit,
then the one leading them must be you, Jiang Shengqiang.
Think about it carefully.
What a headache.
Come in.
Professor Zhang came to teach the training team today.
He also observed their various training sessions.
I heard Deputy Army Commander Liang invited him.
He said he hopes to get support from experts
to help expedite the establishment
of the New Quality Combined Force.
I think that's the idea.
Professor Zhang was my graduate advisor.
So he shared with me privately
his views on this matter.
What did he say?
Personally, I feel
he doesn't seem very optimistic about it.
He said our planning for the training force,
aside from the different equipment,
is basically the Special Forces battalion model
with no qualitative difference.
Not to mention,
the development of air assault forces
is already gradually maturing.
So he thinks
there's no need to overcomplicate things.
What kind of logic is that?
No, I'm going to talk to him.
He's already left.
This afternoon, the superiors will hold
a feasibility meeting on this issue.
He was invited to attend.
Why didn't you tell me earlier?
What if...
There is no "what if."
Knowing him like I do,
he'll definitely voice his opposition.
This Professor Zhang...
We invited him to lecture at the training unit before.
And he's not the only one with objections.
He's just their representative.
I know.
Speaking of which,
it was quite a twist of fate.
Originally, your exploration
was just intended for our theater command,
as a trial within the army.
I was still hoping this little ball of dough
would suddenly rise into a big loaf of bread for me one day.
But with your challenge match causing such a stir,
plus the Special Forces getting involved,
this fire wrapped in paper
could no longer stay hidden.
Thinking about it now,
this challenge match
was a bit impulsive.
However,
we are willing to accept
the questioning from all the experts
and higher authorities,
or even their rejection.
In recent years,
the army has had
many ideas for reform and innovation.
But looking across the world,
they all seem to have hit a bottleneck,
limited by geographical environments
and troop combinations,
and also limited by
the influence of inherent combat modes.
Therefore,
armies of all countries
are eager for a breakthrough,
an effective breakthrough at that.
Our exploration
can't avoid these hurdles.
Actually,
the higher authorities
saw exactly
the changes and opportunities brought by this exploration,
which is why they pay more attention to it.
In the long run,
it's a good thing.
Comrade Chief,
let's leave the long-term things to time.
I'm just asking what to do right now.
We can't just give up halfway, right?
Beihua,
you've been serving as Deputy Army Commander
for four years now, right?
More than four years.
I've already finished my fourth year.
Look at this momentum,
your drive is still as strong as ever.
You know me.
I can't do things the slow and steady way.
I called you here,
firstly, to discuss
the progress of this matter.
Secondly, to ask for your opinion.
If you have concerns,
then I'll just
get a younger cadre to take charge.
What do you mean, Chief?
Are you saying
I should just sit in an office starting today,
attend meetings, make reports,
and quietly wait for a promotion from above?
How did my words get twisted like that in your mouth?
I appreciate your care.
Fine,
then I'll just cut to the chase.
As for building the new-type forces,
we will do it,
and what's more,
we'll see it through to the end.
That's exactly what I was waiting to hear.
Don't cheer just yet.
That fireball in the stove in front of you,
whether it's steel or iron,
and what its quality is,
I have to see for myself.
I can't just easily give it a pass.
Fine.
Tell me in advance which day you're going.
So I can prepare for you.
No need to prepare.
And you are not allowed to prepare.
You, a high-ranking leader,
are actually doing surprise inspections?
Cut the crap. Old rules.
You've read both of their plans.
Which one do you think is more suitable?
I'd say
they both have their merits.
It really is a tough choice.
Currently,
our idea to establish the New Quality Combined Force
is facing some differing opinions.
The army group's intention
is to use this presentation
to change the views of some comrades.
So this final training report
is extremely crucial.
We aim to use this brand-new model
to make the combined structure of new-type combat forces
much clearer.
In this regard,
I believe
Guo Zijian's plan
is superior.
Lao Suo,
I know you have concerns,
but this time,
we must focus on the big picture.
I agree.
Then this time,
let's have Guo Zijian
take charge of our final training report.
The special reconnaissance unit's operation has begun.
For your viewing convenience,
we have switched the view to
the micro-cameras on the soldiers' helmets
and the accompanying footage.
Lao Liang.
This isn't the designated exercise area.
This is our group army's special ammunition depot.
Yeah.
I just noticed that too.
To avoid interfering with
Guo Zijian and his team's creative ideas,
I didn't make them report in advance
the subjects of this exercise.
I didn't expect their first shot
to hit the group army's
most heavily guarded special ammo depot.
Team Two, be advised.
Two roving sentries inside the ammo depot.
Their patrol route
goes from the east second-floor stairs to the west ground level.
A single patrol takes
about five minutes,
with a two-minute interval.
Recon detachment
has completed its reconnaissance on
Ammunition Depot No. 29.
All facilities and passages inside and outside the depot,
along with the ammunition storage status,
have all been captured in data and images.
Mission well done. Prepare to return to base.
Yes, sir.
Commanders,
please adhere to the observation rules.
We have just intercepted
an attempt to use a text message
to tip off the ammunition depot.